Montgomery C. Meigs Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Addition I: Correspondence, Military Orders, and Related Matter, 1836-1890 (Box 38-47, Reel 11-20**)
  - General (Box 38, Reel 11**)
    - 1864, Jan.-July, (2 folders)
    - 1864, Aug.-Dec., undated, (2 folders) (Box 40, Reel 13**)
    - 1865, Jan.-July (Box 41, Reel 13**)
    - 1865, Aug.-Dec.
    - 1866, (2 folders)
    - 1867, (2 folders)
    - 1868
    - 1869, (2 folders) (Box 42, Reel 13**)
    - 1870-1874
    - 1875-1876 (Box 42, Reel 14**)
    - 1877-1890
    - Undated and unidentified
  - Letterbooks
    - 1867, letters from Europe
    - 1879, Oct.-1881, June (Box 43, Reel 14**)
    - 1881, June-1882, Mar. (Box 44, Reel 15**)
    - 1883, Apr.-1884, Feb. (Box 45, Reel 16**)
    - 1884 (Box 46, Reel 17**)
      - Mar.-June
      - June-Dec. (Box 46, Reel 18**)
    - 1884, Dec.-1885, June (Box 47, Reel 18**)
    - 1885, June-Dec. (Box 47, Reel 19**)
    - 1889, June-1890 (Box 47, Reel 20**)
- Addition I: Miscellany, 1815-1971 (Box 48-50, Reel 20-23**)
  Biographical data; insurance, estate, and financial matter; specifications and contract material regarding the building of the Washington Aqueduct; drawings, sketches, and watercolors; house design data collected by Meigs; and miscellaneous photographs and printed matter.
  - Biographical sketch and memorial record, 1892, undated (Box 48, Reel 20**)
  - Check stubs, 1854-1856
  - Design for houses, 1867 See Oversize
  - Drawings and sketches, 1835-1876, undated See Oversize
  - Drawings and watercolors, 1835-1876, undated See also Oversize
  - Estate account book, 1892
  - Estate of G. L. Meigs, 1894-1895, undated
  - Insurance papers, 1846-1869, 1891-1901, undated
  - Li cinque ordini di Architettura del Vignola (Milano, 1863 )
  - Military pay vouchers, 1867-1868
  - Photographs, 1866-1870, undated See also Oversize
  - Printed matter, 1815-1971 See also Oversize (Box 48, Reel 21**)
  - Real estate, 1867-1886 See also Oversize (Box 49, Reel 21**)
    - 1 of 2
    - 2 of 2
  - Receipts from European trip, 1868
  - Washington Aqueduct, Washington, D.C., specifications and contracts (Box 49, Reel 22**)
    - 1857
    - 1858 (Box 50, Reel 22**)
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3
  - Oddments and fragments, 1855-1861, 1873, undated
- Addition II: Miscellany, 1845-1891 (Box 51-52)
  An inscribed Book of Common Prayer, correspondence, poetry by John Rodgers Meigs, and translated texts of shorthand journals.
  Arranged alphabetically by title or type of material.
  - Book of Common Prayer, inscribed, 1845, 1861 (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1879, 1891
  - Poem by John Rodgers Meigs, photocopy and typewritten transcript, circa 1859-circa 1863, undated
  - Transcripts of shorthand journals, undated
    - Index
    - Vol. 1, 1853-1854
    - Vol. 2, 1855
    - Vol. 3, 1856 (Box 52)
    - Vol. 4, 1857
    - Vol. 5, 1858
    - Vol. 6, 1859, 1861
- Oversize, 1835-1885 (Box OV 1-OV 10)
  Drawings, watercolors, plans, photographs, maps, and printed matter, some of which were removed from bound volumes.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed after filming. Some items from Addition I: Miscellany were filmed as separated oversize material rather than in their original locations.
  - Diaries, journals and notebooks (Box OV 1)
    - Journals
      - 1857 (Container 10, Reel 13*)
      - 1860 (Container 12, Reel 15*)
  - Correspondence, military orders, and related matter
    - General, 1867, 1875 (Container 15, Reel 16*)
  - Miscellany
    - Account books, 1879 (Container 19, Reel 24*)
    - Drawings, 1876-1879 (Container 21, Reel 25*)
    - Maps, 1864, 1882, 1889, undated (Container 22, Reel 25*) (Box OV 2)
    - Printed matter
      - Pamphlets, 1867, 1885, undated (Container 24, Reel 26*)
    - Scrapbooks
      - Pension Office building, Washington, D.C., 1882-1883 (Container 24, Reel 26*)
      - War miscellany, 1861, undated (Container 24, Reel 26*)
    - Sketches, 1856-1860, undated (Container 25, Reel 27*) (Box OV 3)
  - Addition I: Family papers
    - Meigs, John Rogers
      - Other papers
        - Report on First Battle of Bull Run, Va., 1861 (Container 27, Reel 2**)
    - Meigs, Montgomery C. (1816-1892)
      - Correspondence
        - Meigs, Charles Delucena, 1861 (Container 31, Reel 5**)
    - Meigs, Montgomery (1847-1931)
      - Other papers
        - Lecture book from Stuttgart Polytechnic, Stuttgart, Germany, 1867-1868 (Container 37, Reel 11**)
  - Addition I: Miscellany (Box OV 4)
    - Design for houses, 1867 (Container 48, Reel 23**)
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3 (Box OV 5)
      - 3 of 3 (Box OV 6)
    - Drawings and sketches, 1835-1876, undated (Container 48, Reel 20 **) (Box OV 7)
    - Drawings and watercolors, 1835-1876, undated (Container 48, Reels 20** and 23**) (Box OV 8)
    - Drawings and sketches, 1835-1876, undated (Container 48, Reel 20 **) (Box OV 9)
    - Photographs, 1866-1870, undated (Container 48, Reels 20** and 23**) (Box OV 10)
    - Printed matter, 1865 (Container 48, Reel 21**)
    - Real estate, 1867, 1879 (Container 49, Reel 21**)